hi everyone this is joe brewer your host
here
at earth regenerators i thought it might
be nice to give you a brief
video update because it's just more
friendly to let you know some of what's
going on here
they're really two sets of activities
that are
changing how earth regenerators works
that are both exciting and invigorating
but also
can be a little confusing one of them is
that
we've just started a community
regenerators
training program or a mutual learning
journey
where almost 40 members of this
community
have joined uh joined diego galli
and me on a journey of discovery to see
how can we
form a decentralized leadership team
and develop new capacities for the
network and this
started last week and we're going to be
exploring the framework of pro-social
and how to create effective groups
and a lot of our work will focus on how
to design
tools and frameworks for better
collaboration across this platform
to serve all of the projects that are
more than 2 000 members
around the world are trying to make
progress on
and make impacts in their local
communities
so we have some really beautiful
conversations that have just
started and we will give you updates as
we go
to let you know what we're learning and
what we're trying to accomplish and
service to all of you
so that'll be coming soon the other
thing that's happening
is here in barichara in colombia where
my family lives
we have begun the process of forming a
foundation
and this grew out of several years of
thinking of course
it's not a completely you know new idea
but a few weeks ago we visited a piece
of heavily degraded land
that is in a strategic area related to
the system of aquifers
the place that brings all of the water
to the village of bodhichara
and also to the nearby village of
villanueva
and this degraded land was something
that was so inspiring to see how
how badly damaged it is and that it's
actually
uh for sale and is at a reasonable price
and i posted on facebook
commenting about wanting to liberate
this land to my surprise
people started offering to donate money
and so we've now raised some money
through these gifts
to be able to start talking with the
current owners
and try to negotiate a price to buy this
land and set up a land trust
and this really compelled us to take
action and start
formally setting up this foundation to
talk with
lawyers who understand how land trusts
work in this region
and we're now developing a framework
that has several
models of cooperation that we want to
experimentally explore
and set up a research program to study
as we attempt
bioregional regeneration here in this
part of the northern andes
and we have four models of cooperation
that we're going to play with
you know in combinations you could think
of them as elements to mix together
in different contexts and so we have
these four ways that we're currently
thinking about
using this initial piece of land and the
foundation that we're setting up
to really take a lot of what we talk
about on this platform
and put it into practice now the first
framework of cooperation
is the design school the design
institute for regenerating earth
that we've been talking about here in
some of our webinars and in some of the
writings
in the study group that we want to set
up
a design school where people can come
and join real world projects study
bioregional design
and practice regenerative design
practices
within some of the projects that we're
participating in
including this piece of land that we're
going to start negotiating the purchase
of
to set up a land trust and begin
reforestation
so this model of cooperation is for
students and for teachers and trainers
from around the world to be able to
gather around local projects
and help create new ways of creating
value
and creating community development
processes
in service to landscape regeneration
the second framework that we're looking
at is something
like a buyer's club so if you're
familiar with traditional cooperatives
a really proven and effective model is
if a group of families come together and
buy things in bulk
like maybe 10 families come together and
buy you know
100 pounds of rice and then they share
it between each other and they get a
better price
because they're buying in bulk so this
form of cooperation
is very well established and what we're
thinking about is
to take this model and apply it to land
acquisition
that there are people who want to buy
land in the region
and what we'd like to be able to do is
coordinate and bring people together
so that they can either buy land that
then is put into service of
reforestation
or that they can join and collaborate
with some of our
projects or other private landowner
projects
in the region as we're coordinating with
them so this is a way of thinking about
leveraging the power of collective
purchasing and collective agreements to
create larger scale impacts in the
region so we'll be experimenting with
this locally
now a third way that we're thinking
about creating cooperation because we
have four models
the third way that we're thinking about
is to
look at forming a network of forest
reserves
and we actually have some collaborators
that are building a network of forest
reserves
within the green belt that surrounds
body chara right now
so we're using their model as a form of
inspiration
that we'd like to work with and extend
here the idea
is that we will partner with private
landowners and
help them create zoning where they might
identify a section of their land
and that they want to set aside for
native forest and then we can help them
to set up
the legal frameworks of protection as a
nature reserve
which gives them tax-exempt status but
also
restricts their ability to develop on
the land this might even lead in some
cases
to the landowners donating some of the
land to the foundation that we're
setting up
so that we can form a patchwork quilt of
forest reserves
spread across the landscape now also we
have a fourth model that our
family personally is very interested in
which is the model of creating
community food forests where we identify
pieces of land
and we're already working with the
moncora bio parque which is a six and a
half hectare
community forest right on the edge of
bodhichara so it's a model for us to
think with
but here the idea is to invite
a group of families or students part of
the design school
to come together on a larger piece of
land and start to build
a food forest where they would engage in
agroforestry practices to do things like
grow the plants that make natural fibers
for clothing and baskets
as well as construction materials for
natural building
for medicinal plants and for food so
building a native forest for this region
that has all of this knowledge and
skills built into it
and here the idea would be to think of
these food forests as being like a
learning school
embedded in the landscape with the
possibility that one or more families
might engage in intentional living on
the land
or students might come and train in
places
working on these reforestation projects
where families may also be living
so the idea is that the community food
forest becomes the model of cooperation
for the people involved in it so these
are the four models that we're thinking
about right now
and i want to share them with you to
show that as we're developing our
capacities to coordinate
on the platform in a decentralized and
geographically spread
way all around the planet that we're
still very devoted
to creating models of bioregional
development
that seek to create regenerative local
economies
and that we're really prototyping this
very actively here in northern columbia
with the goal to have this become one of
the learning centers
that becomes part of a global network
that grows out of these efforts
or that connects with existing efforts
that are deeply aligned
so i just wanted to give you this little
update that these are two of the things
that are going on
and this is why we have fewer live
sessions right now
we're we've reduced the number of
webinars from two
per month down to one per month and
there's a little bit less activity
visually happening
on the platform because we're very busy
with these two focus areas
but i wanted to just give you this
update and let you know more of what's
going on
because we're still working very hard to
develop upon
all that we've built so far this year so
thank you for being here and being
present
if you have comments or reactions please
share them in the comment thread below
and if you want to get involved in any
of this work in some way
please also make comments below or send
me a private message
and we can find a way to talk so thank
you very much and i look forward to
regenerating the earth with all of you
onward
fellow humans